Register of the Jan Fryling Papers, 1939-1977
Hoover Institution Archives
Jan Fryling Papers,
1939-1977
77070
Fryling, Jan
6 manuscript boxes (2.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diaries, speeches and writings, notes, clippings, correspondence, and photographs relating to political events in Poland, Polish foreign relations with China and India, Poland's role in World War II, and activities of Poles in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Poles--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; China.; China--Foreign relations--Poland.; India.; India--Foreign relations--Poland.; Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations--China.; Poland--Foreign relations--India.; Poland--Politics and government--1918-1945.; United States.; Diplomats--Poland.
Container List
- POLISH EMBASSY IN CHUNGKING, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - Decoded telegrams from London, from the Polish Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Exile, addressed to Ambassador Poninski, 1944 February-November
  - Correspondence and reports from Chungking, 1944-1945
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1950-1973 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and reports of Jan Fryling, unofficial representative of the Polish Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Exile, in India and West Bengal; Calcutta-Darjeeling, 1950-1955
  - General correspondence, New York, 1961-1973
- WRITINGS, 1956-1965 (Box 3-4)
  - Jan Fryling's writings for Radio Free Europe; literary programs, weekly book reviews, reviews of plays
  - Writings for the émigré press in London; background material, notes, working copies, miscellany
- DIARIES, 1944-1973 (1944-1947, 1955-1956, 1958, 1963, 1965-1966, 1968-1969, 1972-1973). Diaries cover Jan Fryling's years in Nationalist China, as councilor of the Polish Embassy in Chungking (1944-1945); later as unofficial representative of the Polish Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Exile, in India and West Bengal, and later, his years in New York; as executive director of the Jozef Pilsudski Institute in New York; writer and contributor to the Polish émigré press in London and Radio Free Europe (Box 5-6)